Mancini Nicola Francesco

Bologna, Italy | nicomancini99@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | (+39) 3468575805 (Mobile)

SUMMARY

Passionate **Electronic Engineering student** with a focus on **IoT**, **Machine Learning**, **AI**, and **Data Analysis**. Proven track record of designing and implementing advanced **Machine Learning algorithms** to solve complex real-world challenges, as showcased in the published **IEEE project**. Committed to continuous innovation, research, and development for **ML advancements**.

EDUCATION

Alma Mater Studiorum - University of Bologna

Bologna, Italy

Master of Science in **Electronic Engineering**

Focus in Electronics for Intelligent Systems, Big-Data, and Internet of Things

Current

- Relevant Coursework: IoT, Deep Learning, Optimization and Machine Learning, Intelligent Sensor Systems.
- Relevant Projects: Developed a CNN for Vibration Anomaly Detection, achieving data compression over
 125x and classification accuracy above 90%, as documented in the IEEE publication. Realized an IoT Full Noise Monitoring System with predictive capabilities, NLP Sentence Reconstruction using deep learning techniques, enhancing data interpretability.

UNISANNIO - University of Sannio

Benevento, Italy

Bachelor's Degree in **Electronic Engineering** for **Automation** and Telecommunications

Sep 2018 - Dec 2021

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

• Regularly attend industry webinars and workshops on **Data Science**, **IoT**, and **Machine Learning** advancements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nuove Architetture Case in Legno srl

San Giorgio del Sannio (BN), Italy

Google Ads Specialist, **SEO Strategist and Data Analyst**, Website Manager

Jan 2019 - Current

• Achievements: Ensured website security. Managed and enhanced Google AdWords campaigns efficacy, increasing conversions by 20%. Applied Google Analytics and Data Visualization tools for in-depth marketing analysis, reducing bounce rates by 15% and raising session times by 10%. Analyzed data patterns to optimize SEO, using data-driven strategies, and increased organic search ranking by 35%.

Occasional Freelancer

San Giorgio del Sannio (BN), Italy

AR Creator

Sep 2018 - Current

- **Brands Collaborations**: Loma Vista Recordings (for the Artists: Soccer Mommy, DJDS)
- Relevant Projects: Most liked **IG Filter** at the Warner contest "IG Filter for Dua Lipa's song Hallucinate",

Centro Regionale Information Communication Technology - CeRICT scrl

Benevento, Italy

Electronic Engineering Intern

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

- *Achievements:* Designed a temperature sensor using Bragg grating with FDM 3D-printed plastics. Worked on the periodic monitoring of infrastructures to detect anomalies by **Analyzing Data** from sensors.
- **Projects:** Design and construction of a temperature sensor, integrating Bragg lattice (FBG) in plastic materials through FDM 3D printing, with increased sensitivity

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Technical: Python, Machine Learning, Data visualization, Arduino, MatLab, C++, SEO, WordPress.

Soft: Collaborative Team Player, Strong Analytical Thinker, Data-Driven Decision Maker, Independent Worker, Effective Communicator

Languages: Italian (Native), English (Full Professional), French (Elementary)

Interests: AI, AR, IoT, 3D Printing, Robotics, Reading, VideoGames, Anime, Arts & Culture.